

# **Callum Dreniw**

# Web Developer, Designer And Optimisation Specialist

I am a highly motivated member of the conversion rate optimisation industry with a keen interest in solving problems and working with user experience alongside accessibility at the forefront of my work. I relish the opportunity to learn new methods, techniques, and skills in and around my line of work. Settling for nothing less than the highest standard of work is imperative and engaging my initiative with any resources provided is of second nature to me.

I conduct vast amounts of a/b tests for a variety of compainies both globally and nationally. These include some of the UK's biggest companies in multiple markets, all aiming to improve their key performance indicators.

User experience and data analytics are of the utmost importance relating to the optimisation of the client's websites; resulting in a high standard of efficiency and effectiveness throughout.

# **Employment**

January 2020 - Present

# **Senior Optimisation Executive**

Dentsu Aegis Network

Working as a Senior Optimisation Executive in the Conversion Rate Optimisation (CRO) department, in the web development team, I am:

- Implementing automation processes for an efficient and effective team workstream from our agile briefing process to our development qa testing process.
- Mentoring team members within the development team to ensure they are supported, producing test builds to the highest standards, and enjoying their job.
- Implementing self-development time for our developers to ensure they can widen their knowledge and learning.
- Implementing and developing an internal development core template for a standardised process for an efficient and effective development process.
- Coding/developing vast amounts of tests using JavaScript, jQuery, and SASS.
- Working closely gathering and understanding information from qualitative and quantitative methods.
- Carrying out site speed audits and recommendations for clients' websites.
- · Leading clients strategy creation for a/b testing.

February 2018 – January 2020

# **Optimisation Executive**

Dentsu Aegis Network

- Lead developer on several of our biggest clients.
- · Communicated daily with clients.

**a** callumdreniw.co.uk

✓ callumdreniw@outlook.com

**J** 07557227528

Manchester, England

#### Skills & Knowledge

#### Development

HTML5 | CSS3 | SASS | JavaScript | ES6 | jQuery | Webpack | NodeJS | PHP | MySql

#### **Tools & Technologies**

VWO | Monetate | Google Optimize | Git | Adobe XD, Photoshop & Illustrator | Sketch | InVision | AWS

# Data, Design & Research

Google Analytics | Adobe Analytics | Remote User Research | Moderated User Research | Polls & Surveys | Card Sorting | A/B Testing | UX & UI Design | Data Analysis & Insights | Site Speed

#### Certifications

Baymard E-Commerce UX
Professional (July 2019)
Contentsquare Partner Certification
(December 2019)
Google Analytics Individual
Qualification (May 2020)

#### **Interpersonal Skills**

Communication | Commercial Awareness | Team Working | Leadership | Problem Solving | ICT Skills | Management Experience | Deadline Success

#### **Driving**

UK Driving License (B,B1) August 2012

#### **Interests**

Fitness | Traveling | UX | Photography | Technology | Volunteering | Fundraising

- · Reported on a/b test build updates, a/b test performance and next steps, feasibility and much more whilst ensuring highest standards were always maintained.
- · Shared my knowledge from several testing tools, the front-end development process for testing and conducting site speed audits with the team.
- · Shared my wider optimisation knowledge outside of the development remit within UX design and research methodologies.

September 2016 – February 2018

# **Conversion Rate Optimisation Assistant.**

Dentsu Aeais Network

- · Demonstrated my coding skills ability, gained a greater understanding of optimisation and what it incorporates.
- · Carried out vast amounts of a/b tests and personalisation campaigns.
- · Used Google Analytics to understand the data and performance of testing campaigns and the overall site performance.

July 2015 – September 2016

**Junior Web Developer** Strand Creative (Part-Time)

June 2016 – September 2016

**Assistant Manager** The Moorfield (Part-Time)

July 2011 – June 2016

**Bartender and Waiter** The Moorfield (Part-Time)

November 2014 – July 2016

**Student Ambassador** Manchester Metropolitan University (Part-Time)

#### **Education**

2013-2016

(1st) First Class Honours: BSc (Hons) Information and Communications Manchester Metropolitan University Awarded 'The Programs Leaders Prize' for outstanding achievement

2011-2013

A-Level's Achieved: Subsidiary BTEC Media (Distinction), Business Studies (D), ICT (D) Blessed Thomas Holford Sixth Form (Altrincham)

2006-2011

9 GCSE's A-C

Blessed Thomas Holford (Altrincham)

# **Previous Work & Voluntary Experience**

Modern English (Ad-tech agency) Wythenshawe Hospital (IT department) Lourdes (Shrewsbury Diocese) 2012, 2013 & 2014

Media Vest (Marketing Agency) St Joseph's Parish Youth Club Volunteer Fair-Trade Sales Assistant & Head of Stock

